# Luiz Berilo Casemiro Queiroz

#### **Backend Software Engineer**

+55 85 989071945 berilo.queiroz@gmail.com Fortaleza, BR in/beriloqueiroz github.com/beriloqueiroz

## **Profile**

Fullstack Developer with over 4 years of experience in software development. Experience in various technologies including Java, Spring Boot, Go, Node.js, React, and Svelte. Proficient in agile practices and development methodologies such as TDD, SOLID, Clean Architecture, and Design Patterns. Proven experience in e-commerce environments. Committed to problem-solving with a focus on business strategy-aligned results.

## **Skills**

Java Springboot, Go/Golang, Javascript, NodeJs, typescript, C# .NET, HTML, CSS MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful API, Testing, gRPC, Microservices, Docker SOLID, Clean Architecture, Git, DDD Scrum, Kanban

Kubernetes, AWS Ec2 RDS, Google Cloud Run Teamwork, Communication, Problem Analysis, Business Vision, Commitment

# **Professional Experience**

## FullStack Developer II Buson

— 03/2023 - Present

- FullStack development using HTML, CSS, Javascript, Nodejs, Typescript, VueJs, Svelte, Handlebars, Java, Spring Boot.
- Worked in the e-commerce squad, handling deployment procedures, troubleshooting build errors in Jenkins and Argos, and deploying to production using Kubernetes.

#### FullStack Developer Buson

*— 05/2022 - 02/2023* 

- FullStack development using HTML, CSS, Javascript, Nodejs, Typescript, VueJs, Svelte (POC), Handlebars, Java, Spring Boot.
- Worked in the POS and e-commerce squad.

## FullStack Developer and Director Maquiadoro

*— 01/2021 - 04/2022* 

- Backend development in NodeJs, Typescript, focusing on SOLID principles and clean architecture.
- Used Docker, MongoDB, Postgres, and MySQL.
- Frontend work in ReactJs on some projects. Maintenance of the e-commerce frontend.
- Technology consulting and IT team leadership, applying agile SCRUM methodology.

#### PO/Developer and Director Maguiadoro

*— 05/2019 - 12/2020* 

- Acted as Product Owner and developer in the IT team, applying agile SCRUM methodology.
- Developed microsystems for process management and automation.
- Technology consulting and IT team leadership.

#### **E-commerce and Operations Director** *Maquiadoro*

*— 08/2018 - 01/2019* 

- Responsible for data analysis and metrics, setting goals based on strategic planning.
- Process mapping, fiscal and tax analysis.
- Business metrics monitoring.

#### Commercial Director and Logistics/Shipping Director Maquiadoro

*— 07/2016 - 07/2018* 

- Expanded logistics and managed the commercial sector.
- Sales analysis, procurement team management, fiscal and tax analysis.
- Process automation and company modernization.

## Mechatronics Engineer Nexo Engenharia

*— 09/2015 - 06/2016* 

- Developed and executed projects in building and industrial automation.
- Developed programs for Programmable Logic Controller (PLC) and automation systems.
- Supervisory software configuration.

## Automation Systems Analyst Nexo Engenharia

- Developed programs for Programmable Logic Controller (PLC) and automation systems.
- Supervisory software configuration.
- Participation in building and industrial automation projects.

#### Automation Assistant Nexo Engenharia

- Developed programs for Programmable Logic Controller (PLC) and automation systems.
- Supervisory software configuration.
- Automation system start-up.

#### Intern Nexo Engenharia

- Developed programs for Programmable Logic Controller (PLC) and automation systems.
- Supervisory software configuration.
- Quantity surveying and project points documentation.

#### **Scholarship Holder** Laboratório de Processamento de Energia - LPE (IFCE)

Development of projects in the field of power electronics, control, and wind energy.

#### Intern TS Tecnologia e soluções em automação industrial LTDA

- Analysis of industrial automation systems.
- Programming of Programmable Logic Controllers (PLCs).
- Development of supervisory systems.

## Courses & Certifications

- Clean Architecture module (2023) FullCycle
- Hexagonal Architecture module (2023) FullCycle
- Web Application Security (2023) Udemy
- Event Storming module (2022) FullCycle
- Communication between systems module (2022) FullCycle
- Domain-Driven Design (DDD) module (2022) FullCycle
- SOLID Express module (2022) FullCycle
- Software Architecture Fundamentals module (2022) FullCycle
- Docker module (2022) FullCycle
- HTML, CSS, Javascript (2021-2022) Rocketseat
- Node.js, TypeScript, RESTful API (Express) (2021-2022) Rocketseat ignite
- React (2021-2022) Rocketseat ignite
- HTML Basic Training (2020-2021) LinkedIn Learning
- Project Budget Management (2020-2021) LinkedIn Learning
- Project Schedule Management (2020-2021) LinkedIn Learning
- Industry 4.0: Fundamentals of the Fourth Industrial Revolution (2020-2021) LinkedIn Learning
- Fundamentals of Artificial Intelligence: Machine Learning (2020-2021) LinkedIn Learning
- Remote Software Development (2020-2021) LinkedIn Learning
- III Consultant Training Program (2020-2021) DOMANI
- Elipse E3 Developers (2015) Elipse Software
- Short Course in Configuration and Project Development of CCTV (2015) Axis Communications

- 01/2015 - 09/2015

*— 06/2014 - 01/2015* 

**—** 12/2012 - 06/2014

- 2012 - 2014

**—** 11/2011 - 05/2012

• Java SE (2010) - Centro de Pesquisa e Qualificação Tecnológica

# **Education**

Postgraduate (Go Language) Full Cycle Technology College — 2023-2024

Postgraduate - MBA in Project and Process Management IPOG — 2020-2021

Bachelor's Degree - Mechatronics Engineering IFCE, Brazil — 2008-2015

# Languages

• English [Intermediate]

Portuguese [Native]